MATT WILEY

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | TECH LEAD | MENTOR 859.206.0007 | matt.wiley@fastmail.com | Fort Thomas, KY

SUMMARY

Software engineer with a passion for continuous improvement and automation and over ten years experience across the full software development stack. Seeking opportunity to join a diverse team of engineers to learn from, lead and mentor while delivering well-crafted solutions to business problems.

EDUCATION

BS in Computer Science Northern Kentucky University College of Informatics December 2012

STRENGTHS

Leadership Coaching Strategic Thinking Process Improvement

Java
Python
Git
Shellscript
Linux
VS Code
IntelliJ IDEA
GitHub Actions

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

Reading Drawing, Painting, Making Writing Learning Solving puzzles

Physics & Cosmology Fiction & Sci-Fi PBS Spacetime PBS Eons

LINKS

matt-wiley
in/matt-b-wiley
@matt.wiley.person
matt-wiley.github.io

EXPERIENCE

Lead Software Engineer 84.51°

Aug 2018 - Present

Providing technical leadership and individual contribution across multiple initiatives. Developing tools ranging from the web UI and provisioning API for a cloud-based data science platform to a DevSecOps framework to enable and accelerate application development.

- Led a team of co-ops and contractors in delivering the web UI of an internal data science
 platform, achieving first business-value projects on platform inside 6 months, and mentoring
 2 co-ops into full-time positions
- Launched service and automation tools to collect and assess repository metrics enabling
 migration of 3K+ repos from on premise to cloud, archival of 15K+ repos to inactive storage,
 and saving nearly 6 months of manual migration effort
- Instituted component discovery portal documenting 60+ reusable components and their usages, and promoting an innersource contribution model for use by the Engineering function at large
- Engineered a YAML-based, declarative CLI tool for easily stamping out new TeamCity pipelines, reducing pipeline construction time by 80%
- Established template-based Docker image build system for creating secure, enterprisecompliant Docker images and reducing lead time on new image creation by 75%

Senior UI Developer 84.51°

Jul 2015 - Aug 2018

Spearheaded software development efforts for the R&D Studio team. Created bleeding-edge, highly-personalized customer experiences for voice assistant, augmented reality, virtual reality, web and mobile devices.

- Created a category management experience showing that virtual reality could allow a
 category manager to make edits on a specific shelf in a specific store, and leverage forecast
 analysis to see impact of potential changes
- Delivered an experience for the Microsoft Hololens demonstrating the opportunity to display data in the real world view of a category manager live in the store
- Devised an augmented reality experience to illustrate how a standard paper weekly ad could be enhanced with user data to create a real-time personalized weekly ad

Consultant, Senior I Cardinal Solutions Group

Jan 2013 - Jul 2015

Collaborated with stakeholders within businesses to create or enhance applications and unlock critical business value. Worked with various clients to design, build and document solutions to technical problems.

 Programmed flexible, Java-based system for ingesting hundreds of gigabytes of data from multiple sources, and transforming them into personalized weekly ad results delivered to over 40 million customers across the US